Guide to the Regina Derieva papers, 1949-2015 M2034
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Regina Derieva papers
1949-2015
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Derieva, Regina
Deriev, Alexander
M2034
4.67 Linear Feet (9 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box)
Biogaphical Note
Regina Derieva (1949-2013) was a Russian poet with over thirty published works of poetry, prose, and fiction. Born in Odessa, Ukraine, Derieva started to write poetry at age of 15. From 1960 until 1991 she lived and worked in Akmolinsk (Tselinograd / Akmola) and Karaganda, Kazakhstan. She graduated from university with majors in music and Russian philology and literature. In 1990 Regina and her family converted to Catholicism and soon moved to Israel. From July 1999 until her death on December 11, 2013, Derieva lived in Sweden. Regina Derieva's work was highly valued by Joseph Brodsky, Tomas Venclova, Les Murray, Daniel Weissbort, Bengt Jangfeldt and many other poets and intellectuals.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence (only incoming letters), writings, personal papers (including legal records and documents), audio material, photography archive, drawings and paintings, newspaper clippings and printed materials, spanning the years 1949-2015.
Arrangement
The papers are divided into 12 separate series: 1) Biographical file; 2) Correspondence; 3) Writings; 4) Regina Derieva's poetry translated into different languages, by others; 5) Translations of poetry into Russian by Regina Derieva; 6) Regina Derieva as an editor; 7) Printed matter of contemporaries, signed by Regina Derieva; 8) Art work; 9) Photographs; 10) Audio materials and born-digital materials; 11) Miscellaneous; and 12) Bibliography
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was given by Alexander Deriev to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2014.
Russian literature -- 20th century; Russian literature -- 21st century; Russian poetry.; Derieva, Regina; Deriev, Alexander
- Series 1. Biographical file, 1949-2014
  - Certificates, diplomas and membership cards, 1949-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Documents from the Israeli High Court of Justice and other institutions regarding immigration status, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Denial of Israeli citizenship: newspaper articles, 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Catholic Church and legal problems in Israel: documents and correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Obtaining of the Swedish citizenship, 2000-2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The preparation for an interview, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Recommendation letters, agreements and related documents, 1980-2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Writings about Regina Derieva: articles, 1993-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Writings about Regina Derieva by Wolfgang Kasack, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Poetry readings and writers' festivals: invitations, programs, clippings and related materials, 1999-2010 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Obituaries and post-mortem publications, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series 2. Correspondence, 1972-2014
  - Arnold, Kenneth, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bernstein Ilya, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bourne, Daniel, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brazhentseva, Yuliia, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brodsky, Joseph, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Canavan, Kathleen, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fainlight, Ruth, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Finch, Annie, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - France, Peter, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Genn, Nina, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Grip, Robert, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Harris, Susan, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Jangfeldt, Bengt, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jangfeldt, Bengt, 2004-2005, 2007, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kaminsky, Ilya, 2009-2010, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Kasack, Wofgang, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Kates, Jim, 2004-2013 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Kilcourse, George, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kinsella, John, 2003-2014 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Kushner, Alexander Semyonovich, 1980, 2005-2006, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lasdun, James, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lossky Veronique, 1999, 2004-2013 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lyn, Lim Yi etc. from Singapore, 2007-2008, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - McKane, Richard, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Michaelides, Lily, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Morkus, Jonas, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mulner-Gulland, Robin, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Murray, Leslie Allan alias Les Murray, 2002-2014 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nordstrom, Lisa, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Nugent, Eugene M., 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Paguio, Erlinda G., 2003 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pann, Lily, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Persson, Malte, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Petrova (Terentieva), Larisa, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Polukhina, Valentina, 2003-2013 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Popov, Yevgeni Anatolyevich, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Prufer, Kevin, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ramm, Benjamin, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reid, Robert, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Rozewicz, Tadeusz, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rubinstein, Natalia, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Samoylov, David, 1976-1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Sampson, Fiona, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Shaw, Alan, 2000, 2003-2013 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Sheiman, Lev Avrumovich, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Sinkevich, Valentina, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Smock, Frederick, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Soderberg, Lasse, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sundquist, Karin, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Twardowski, Jan, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Venclova, Tomas, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Weissbort, Daniel, 2003-2013 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Yefimov, Igor Markovich, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1999-2005 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series 3. Writings, 1965-2013
  - Handwritten manuscripts, 1972-2013
    - Poetry dedicated to Ljalja (Larisa) Petrova, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Poetry notebook, 2006-2009 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Poetry notebook, 2009-2013 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Children's poetry: notebook, 2007, 2009, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Poetry from "Northeast States" cycle: loose sheets, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Unfinished poem: loose sheets, 2007-2010 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Individual poems: loose sheets, 2012-2013 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Individual poems: loose sheets, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Short autobiographical story "Tochka vozvrata" (The swallowtail point), 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The preparation of the semiautobiographical novel "Only a woman's hair", 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The beginning of short story "Musornaia kucha" (A midden), 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The preparation of two short stories, untitled, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The preparation of the comedy play about Russian emigre, untitled, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The preparation for stories "Natsionalnye traditsii" (National traditions): notes and collected epigraphs, 2001-1008 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Some notes and a drawing, 2001-2008 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Fabricated names for satirical prose characters; titles and notes for some stories, 2008-2011 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Thoughts: notebook, 2005-2013 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Publications in anthologies, 1965-2003
    - Chas poezii. Moskva, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Shutki v storonu: iumor i satira v proze i stikakh. Alma-Ata, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Antologiia russkogo verlibra. Moskva, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Strofy veka: antologiia russkoi poezii. Minsk-Moskva, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Literaturnyi vitrazh: sbornik v chest valentiny Sinkevich. Niu-Iork, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Gorodorog: deistvie mest. Parizh, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Publications in periodicals, 1994-2011
    - Radost voskreseniia=Joy of resurrection. Israel, 1994. N 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Kreschatik: international literary magazine. Moskva-Kiev, 2003. N 1(19) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Vremia i mesto: mezhdunarodnyi literaturno-khudozhestvennyi i obshchestvenno-politicheskii zhurnal. Niu-Iork, 2007. N 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Mesto vstrechi. Cheliabinsk, 2010. N 1(18) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Dom neporochnogo serdtsa. Sankt-Peterburg, 2011. N 1(4) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Monographs, 1978-2006
    - Pocherk: stikhi. Alma-Ata, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Po pereputku: stikhi. Alma-Ata, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Dva neba: stikhotvoreniia. Alma-Ata. 1990. The book announced, but destroyed (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Otsutstvie: stikhi (Absence: verse). Tenafly, N.J., 1993. Cover only (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Prikhod (The visitation). Jerusalem, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Apostoly (The apostoles). Jerusalem, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Krestnyi put (The way of the cross). Jerusalem, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Pavel. Jerusalem, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Raduisia, Mariia (Hail Mary). Jerusalem, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Chudesa gospodni (The miracles of the Lord). Jerusalem, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Posledniaia voina (The last war). London, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Zimnie lektsii dlia terroristov (Winter lectures for terrorists). London, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Molitva dnia (Prayer of the day). Jerusalem, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Begloe prostranstvo. Stockholm, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Sobranie dorog. 2 vol. Sankt-Peterburg, 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Poetry and musical scores, 1998
    - Chin Rimskoi messy dlia russkikh katolikov. Jerusalem, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Via Crucis = The way of the cross: cantata for soloists, choir and organ. Music by Fr Armando Pierucci. Jerusalem, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Via Crucis = The way of the cross: cantata for soloists, choir and organ: programms for performances, booklets and related materials (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Unfinished projects
    - The holy sepulcre: miracles, relics, saints: for the 2000 years of jubilee of birth of Christ (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series 4. Regina Derieva's poetry translated into different languages, by others, 1994-2010
  - Anthologies, 2004-2010
    - Poetry East: features and special issues. Chicago, IL, N 52, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - New European poets. Saint Paul, MN, 2008. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The poet and his world. Nicosia, 2010. In English and Greek (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - An anthology of contemporary Russian women poets. Iowa, IA 2005. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - IOU: new writing on money. Concord, MA, 2010. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Periodicals, 1997-2010
    - La Terra Santa. Jerusalem, 1997 novembre-decembre, 1999 marzo-aprile. In Italian (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Holy Land: illustrated quarterly of the Franciscan Custody of the Holy Land. Jerusalem, 1997 winter. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Artes: tidskrift för litteratur konst och musik. Stockholm, 2000. N 2. In Swedish (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Ars-interpres: an international annual journal of poetry, translation and art. New York-Moscow-Stockholm, 2003-2004. N 1-2. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Ars-interpres: an international annual journal of poetry, translation and art. New York-Moscow-Stockholm, 2004-2005. N 3-4/5. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Ars-interpres: an international annual journal of poetry, translation and art. New York-Moscow-Stockholm, 2006-2007. N 6/7-8/9. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Notre Dame Review. Notre Dame, IN, 2005. N 19. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Trots Allt. Örebro, 2006. N 2. In Swedish (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Aorta: journal för retrogardostisk kultur. Göteborg, 1997. N 13, 15, 16. In Swedish (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Quadrant. Balmain, NSW, Australia, 2007. N 433. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Cyphers. Dublin, 2008. N 66. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - St. Petersburg Review. Concord, NH, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Liberal: poetry, politics, culture. London, 2007 April/May (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - The Dirty Dog. Austin, TX, 2009. N 20 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Artful Dodge. Wooster, OH, 2009. N 48/49 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Poetry International. San Diego, CA, 2010. N 15-16 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Monographs: poetry and prose, 1994-2007
    - Three possibilities to see the kingdom og god: a short apology of Christianity. Jerusalem, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - The meaning of mystery: icons of the holy land: essays and iconographical collection. Jerusalem, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - I nuovi fioretti di S. Francesco: traduzione. Jerusalem, 1998. In Italian and Arabic (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - L' Etoile du Pelerin. Jerusalem, 1999. In French (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - In commemoration of monuments = Pamiati pamiatnikov. Jerusalem, 1999. In Russian and English (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Inland sea and other poems. Jerusalem, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Instructions for silence = Dans le Silence la Louange - Obuchenie molchaniiu. Jerusalem, 1999. In English, French and Russian (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - The pilgrim's star: a collection of litanies and poems for pilggrimage in the Holy Land. South Shield, UK, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The last island = Poslednii ostrov. Stockholm, 2002. In English and Russian (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Himmelens geometri. Stockholm, 2003. In Swedish (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Oavbrutet svarta bilder. Goteborg, 2007. In Swedish (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Allt som tolv kejsare inte hunnit saga = Everything the 12 caesars did not get to say. Stockholm, 2007. In Swedish and English (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Poems. In Chinese (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Series 5. Translations of poetry into Russian by Regina Derieva, 2002-2008
  - Smock, Frederick. Poems = Smok, Frederik. Stikhi. New York., 2002 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Kinsella, John. The sky's imperative = Kinsella, Dzhon. Nebesnyi imperativ. Poetry. New York, Stockholm. In English and Russian, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Le Murray. The end of symbol = Les Marrei. Zavershenie simvola. Poetry. New York, Stockholm. In English and Russian, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Merton, Thomas. New seeds of contemplation = Merton, Tomas. Semena sozertsaniia. Essays. Moskva. In Russian, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. The name's progress = Yaissbort, Deniel. Peremena imeni. Poetry. Stockholm. In English and Russian, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Wastberg, Per. Ortsbestamning = Wastberg, Per. Determination of place = Vestberg, Per. Opredelenie mesta. Poetry. In Swedish, English and Russian, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Series 6. Regina Derieva as an editor, 1999-2015
  - Editors notes: Ars Interpres Publications, 2004-2007 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Skobkin, Vasilii I Sinokrot, Malek Dzhamal. V mire strashnykh myslei. Pod redaktsiei Reginy Derievoi. Jerusalem, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Note by Alexander Deriev regarding Regina Derieva's editor's work, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Series 7. Printed matter of contemporaries, signed for Regina Derieva, 1973-2008
  - Sokolov, Vladimir. Chetvert veka. Moskva; With inscription for Regina Derieva, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Twardowski, Jan. Sumienie ruszylo I nowe wiersze. Warszawa, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Twardowski, Jan. Znaki ufnosci. Warszawa; With inscription for Regina Derieva, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Rozewicz, Tadeusz. Ocalony. Warszawa. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 1999, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Brodsky, Joseph. Primechaniia paporotnika. Bromma, Sweden. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Les Murray. Poems the size of photographs. Sydney. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fainlight, Ruth. Sugar-paper blue. London. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 2006, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Odds and rule. Iowa, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Eel fishing, poems to Ted. Iowa, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Letters to Ted. London. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 2003, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. At sixty. London. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Blasted though thr breastbone. London. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Blather in a bleak season. London. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 2005, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Home. London, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. This at sixty plus. London. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. No comedy. London., 2006 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Etc. London. With inscription for Regina Derieva, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Out. London., 2006 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. In. London, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Beckett twice. London, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Babe or Man. London, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Battle. London, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. After. London, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Oddly enough. London, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. As if lived. London, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Weissbort, Daniel. Sixty. London, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Series 8. Art work, 1994-2008
  - Subseries. Derieva, Regina, 2005-2008
    - Three "Khazar" pictures, painted on canvas with egg-tempera, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Drawing in pencil and pastel "Bunch of tulips", 2007 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Drawings in pencil and pastel from the series of 9 illustrations for the unfinished cycle of poems on Greco-Roman mythology. The title of the cycle " The Unnatural world", 2008 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Art photograph taken by Regina Derieva: "Tattooed face"", 2006 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subsery. Creffield, Dennis, 1994-2002
    - 12 drawings meant to illustrate poems from Regina's Derieva's "Winter lectures for terrorists". Charcoal on paper, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Paintings of Petworth: catalogue. London. With inscription for Regina and Alexander, 2000, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Paintings & drawings of Orford Ness: catalogue. With inscription for Regina and Alexander, 2000, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Impressions of castles: drawings of castles in Wales and England: catalogue. Hay-on-Wye, Hereford, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Subsery. Deriev, Alexander, 2007-2008
    - Art photographs. Edited photographs of Roman coins. These pictures were used as visual material when "Everything the 12 caesars did not get to say" was performed. Published as a book in Stockholm, 2007-2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Art photograph. Photo-portrait of Regina, edited for the book, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series 9. Photographs, 1949-2009
  - Photographs with notes. From e-mail attachment, July 30, 2015, 1949-2009 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Photographs with notes, Israel. From e-mail attachment., 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Photoalbum, 1949-2007 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Series 10. Audio materials. Born-digital, 1997-2011
  - De Profundis: The Art of Dying. Cantata by Armando Pierucci. Texts by Regina Derieva. CD recorded in Jerusalem, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - The last war by Regina Derieva. Poetic pilgrimage to the Holy Land. Chants from the Holy Land. CD recorded in Jerusalem, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Hail Mary: spiritual poems, prayers and Church Slavonic hymns. Author and reader Regina Derieva. Prayers chanted by Father Abraham, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Via Crucis: the way of the cross. Cantata by Armando Pierucci. Texts by Regina Derieva. CD recorded in Lithuania, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Via Crucis. De Profundis. Cantatas by Armando Pierucci. Texts by Regina Derieva. 2 CD recorded in Switzerland, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - DAT Tape (Box 10, Folder 7, Computer media 0)
  - Files sent by donor
    - Regina Derieva Reads for Ryszard Reisner 1, 2010 (Computer media 0)
    - Regina Derieva Reads for Ryszard Reisner 2, 2010 (Computer media 0)
    - Regina Derieva Reads for Ryszard Reisner 3, 2010 (Computer media 0)
    - Regina Derieva Reads for Ryszard Reisner 4, 2010 (Computer media 0)
    - Interview with Bengt Jangfeldt, 2001 (Computer media 0)
  - July 09, 2014 - Photos (Box 10, Folder 8, Computer media 0)
  - July 09, 2014. Disk 1 - Video; Sound (Box 10, Folder 9, Computer media 0)
  - July 09, 2014. Disk 2 - Video; Sound (Box 10, Folder 9, Computer media 0)
  - July 19, 2014 - Photos (Box 10, Folder 8, Computer media 0)
- Series 11. Miscellaneous, 2009
  - Cross, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Medal Ora et Labora awarded by Catholic Church of Sweden, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Series 12. Bibliography, 1965-2015
  - The list of Regina Derieva's publications and related materials. Compiled by Alexander Deriev, 1965-2015 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Regina Derieva Papers described by Alexander Deriev, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Detailed description of audio/video materials, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 6)